Guide to the Staff Newsletter 1961-2009
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
Staff Newsletter
1961-2009
Oregon State University. News and Communication Services.
PUB 008-22a
3.25 cubic feet 9 boxes, including 3 ovesize boxes
Special Collections and Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids
The Staff Newsletter consists of the weekly publication for Oregon State University faculty and staff published from 1961 through 2009 as The Staff Newsletter, OSU This Week, OSU This Summer, and LIFE@OSU. The newsletter includes articles, announcements, and news of campus-wide interest. The Faculty Senate minutes were published as an appendix to the newsletter during the 1960s and 1970s. Most of the issues of OSU This Week and OSU This Summer are available online in Oregon Digital.
Oregon State University. Department of Information.; Oregon State University. Faculty Senate.; Oregon State University. University Advancement.; Oregon State University--Administration.; Oregon State University--Employees.; Oregon State University--Faculty.; Oregon State University. Faculty Senate
Universities and colleges--Oregon--Corvallis--Employees.; Universities and colleges--Oregon--Corvallis--Faculty.
Colleges and Universities; Oregon; Corvallis
These newsletters were received on distribution by the University Archives from the 1960s through 2009.
Collection is open for research.
Issues of the Staff Newsletter from the 1974-1975, 1975-1976, and 1976-1977 academic years are part of the History of OSU book collectiion in the Special Collections and Archives Research Center with the call number LD4337 .A32. An index of Staff Newsletter issues from 1961 to 1971 is also available at that call number. The News and Communication Services Records (RG 203) include extensive biographical files for Oregon State faculty and staff.
The Staff Newsletter is arranged in 4 series: 1. Staff Newsletter, 1961-1987; 2. OSU This Week, 1987-2008; 3. OSU This Summer, 1993-2008; and LIFE@OSU, 2008-2009.
The Staff Newsletter consists of the weekly publication for Oregon State University faculty and staff written, edited, and produced by News and Communications Services (and previously the Department of Information). The newsletter was published weekly during the academic year resulting in about 35 issues per year. Beginning in 1993, a summer edition was published monthly.
The Staff Newsletter launched in September 1961 and the first issue welcomed new Oregon State University President James Jensen. The title was changed to OSU This Week in 1987. In 1994, the publication format changed to tabloid-size printed on newsprint. In 2008, OSU This Week ceased publication and LIFE@OSU, which featured lengthier stories on the people and programs of Oregon State, was produced in print twice per month with an accompanying website. LIFE@OSU ceased publication with the August 13, 2009 issue.
While the content and format of the Staff Newsletter evolved during its nearly 50-year run, the function remained constant – to provide news and announcements to all employees of Oregon State University. To that end, the newsletter included announcements and news of campus-wide interest; reports regarding budgets, new academic programs, gifts and grants received, and other campus programs and activities; a calendar of campus events; and announcements of new administrators and faculty. Information about campus buildings and infrastructure, including new construction and major remodels was included. Notices of retirements, deaths, honors and appointments were often published. With time, more feature stories about Oregon State faculty and staff were published. The annual statewide food drive (in February) and charitable fund drive (in November-December) are prominent in the newsletter at those times of the year.
The Faculty Senate Minutes were distributed as an appendix to the Staff Newsletter in the 1960s and 1970s and are included in this collection for the 1969-1970 through 1973-1974 academic years.
Annual indexes for the staff newsletter are available for the 1961-1962 through 1973-1974 academic years, bound with the issues for each year.
Most of the issues of OSU This Week and OSU This Summer are available online in Oregon Digital.
- Staff Newsletter, 1961-1987; Series 1
  Series 1 consists of the weekly Staff Newsletter for employees of Oregon State University. The Newsletter was published weekly during the academic year and approximately 35 issues were published in the volume for each academic year. The Staff Newsletter included announcements and news of campus-wide interest; reports regarding budgets, academic programs, gifts and grants received, and other campus programs and activities; a calendar of campus events; and announcements of new faculty and administrators. This series includes bound volumes (with an index for the issues in that volume) for 1961-1962 thru 1973-1974 as well as some individual (unbound) issues for those years. The Faculty Senate minutes were distributed as an appendix to the Staff Newsletter and are included in this series for the 1969-1970 academic year (volume 9) through 1973-1974 (volume 13). Only one issue of the Staff Newsletter from the academic years 1974-1975, 1975-1976, and 1976-1977 is available in this series. Those issues are available in the History of OSU book collection.
  - Volume 1, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1.1)
    Bound volume; includes index for this volume.
  - Individual issues from volume 1, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Volume 2, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Individual issues from volume 2, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Volume 3, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 1.5)
    Bound volume. Includes an index for this volume and an addendum about the 1963 tax referral published by the OSU Federation.
  - Individual issues from volume 3, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Volume 4, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2.1)
    Bound volume includes index for this year.
  - Individual issues from volume 4, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Volume 5, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Individual issues from volume 5, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Volume 6, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3.1)
    Bound volume with index for this year.
  - Volume 7, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Individual issues from volume 7, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Volume 8, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Individual issues from volume 8, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Volume 9, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3.6)
    Bound volume with index of the newsletter for this year. Also include Faculty Senate minutes and index to the minutes for 1969-1970.
  - Individual issues from volume 9, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Volume 10, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 4.2)
    Bound volume with index; also includes Faculty Senate minutes and index for 1970-1971.
  - Individual issues from volume 10, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Volume 11, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4.4)
    Bound volume.
  - Individual issues from volume 11, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4.5)
    Includes Faculty Senate minutes for the May 25, 1972 meeting (meeting 287).
  - Volume 12, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 5.1)
    Bound volume with index for this year; also includes Faculty Senate minutes and index of minutes for 1972-1973 meetings.
  - Individual issues from volume 12, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Volume 13, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5.3)
    Bound volume with index of the staff newsletter; also includes Faculty Senate minutes and index for meetings during 1973-1974.
  - Individual issues from volume 13, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - April 22, 1976 Staff Newsletter (Box-folder 5.5)
    Volune 15, no. 27.
  - Volume 17, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Volume 18, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Volume 19, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - Volume 20, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - Volume 21, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Volume 22, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Volume 23, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Volume 24, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Volume 25, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Volume 26, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 6.5)
    Through March 1987.
- OSU This Week, 1987-2008; Series 2
  Series 2 consists of OSU This Week, the weekly faculty and staff newsletter for Oregon State University, that was published weekly during the academic year, with approximately 35 issues published per year. The new title, OSU This Week, debuted in April 1987. Beginning in September 1994, the publication transitioned to a tabloid-sized format on newsprint. OSU This Week included articles about initiatives and programs at Oregon State; announcements of upcoming campus-wide events; notices of import to faculty and staff; a list of academic and classified staff vacancies; and information and campus buildings and facilities, especially new structures and major modifications. Notices of retirements, deaths, honors, and appointments were also included. The newsletter was printed on Tuesdays (with a submission deadline the previous Friday), distributed through campus mail on Wednesdays, and arrived in campus mailboxes on Thursdays. Most of the issues of OSU This Week are available online in Oregon Digital.
  - Volumes 26 and 27, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 6.6)
    Beginning with first issue of OSU This Week in April 1987 and continuing through the 1987-1988 academic year. Includes the Faculty Senate minutes for the March 3, 1988 meeting (meeting 447).
  - Volume 28, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Voume 29, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Volume 30, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Volume 31, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Volume 32, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 6.11)
  - Volume 33, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Volume 34, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Volume 35, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Volume 36, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Volume 37, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Volume 38, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Volume 39, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - Volume 40, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Volume 41, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Volume 42, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Volume 43, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Volume 44, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Volume 45, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Volume 46, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Volume 47, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Final issue of OSU This Week, 2008 (Box-folder 9.4)
    The last issue of OSU This Week was published on September 11, 2008 based on feedback from faculty and staff.
- OSU This Summer, 1993-2008; Series 3
  Series 3 consists of the summer staff newsletter, OSU This Summer. Two or three issues of the newsletter were published each summer beginning in 1993 and continuing through 2008. As with its sibling publication, OSU This Week, the format changed to a tabloid-size on newsprint in 1995. The content included announcements of new initiatives and appointments of new administrators; stories about Oregon State facuty and staff; and calendar notices of upcoming campus-wide events. Most of the issues of OSU This Summer are available online in Oregon Digital.
  - Volumes 1 and 2, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 6.13)
    One issue for 1993 (July) and 3 issues for 1994 (June, July, and August).
  - Volumes 3 thru 10, 1995-2008 (Box-folder 9.5)
    Two or three issues published during the summer.
- LIFE@OSU, 2008-2009; Series 4
  Series 4 consists of LIFE@OSU, the official newsletter for employees at Oregon State University, that was produced in print every other week during the academic year. The content was also available online through an interactive website. This color publication featured stories of the people and programs of Oregon State University and included limited announcements and calendar notices. Production of a print publication ceased with the August 13, 2009 issue and LIFE@OSU transitioned to an online-only publication.
  - Volume 1, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 9.6)
    Nineteen issues published twice per month from September 2008 through August 2009.